Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. This video is not about the
progressive era. It does kind of
establish the roots to the later
progressive movements, but we aren't
quite there yet. The big idea with this
topic is obviously with these horrible
societal inequities. There are going to
be lots of people beginning to push for
reform. This will typically split into a
lot of groups. We're going to talk about
each of them. To start off, socialists
and radical labor leaders like Eugene V.
Debs argued that capitalism exploited
workers and that major industries should
be publicly owned. This group was linked
to many strikes such as the Pullman one
talked about in a previous video. Then
you have the social gospel movement.
People like Washington Gladen will argue
for a religious response to poverty.
They argued Christianity should address
inequality, labor conditions, and urban
poverty. And finally, you have the
utopians, agrarians, and critics. These
movements were less important
individually and had similar arguments,
which is why I'm lumping them all
together. They pretty much all
criticized monopolies, wage labor, and
urban misery. All right, moving on.
Let's talk about women. We already
talked about Jane Adams and her whole
house, but you have to understand in
this time period, women couldn't vote
and had very limited legal power. So, a
response you'll see to this is the
constant use of voluntary organizations
to exert influence. Yes, you have the
reformers. And yes, you have the
organizations. But you see a common
trend of what most women in these
organizations were pushing for
temperance, child labor reform, public
health, education, and anti-ynching
activism. That's all for this one. On
the screen now are AP style questions
for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.